[theme music playing]
BASED ON THE KINGDOM OF THE GODS
[suspenseful music playing]
[clang]
[growling]
[second queen] As you ordered,
all the gates have been sealed.
However,
do you really plan to give up on
the entire region of Gyeongsang?
It does not compare to Jeolla,
which is lush and abundant,
but do you really plan to give up
all the grains
the subjects of Gyeongsang offer up?
Do you regard power...
only as the means of coveting money?
How many dead bodies...
do you think are there
at the bottom of this pond?
Bringing the day
when no one can say a word about
how many bodies I have dumped
in this pond.
That is what power is for.
I will use that power...
to protect you, Father.
I am the one
who placed that power in your hand.
I am also the one
who can take it away from you at any time.
Do not open the gates
until I give the orders.
What about the Crown Prince?
The Crown Prince is still alive
in Gyeongsang.
Do you plan to let him be?
I will...
kill the Crown Prince.
kill him with my own hands.
- Lord Ahn!
- [door closes]
Hand over the Crown Prince.
Cho Hak-ju has closed Mungyeong Saejae.
We need the Crown Prince
if we are to get it open again.
Where is he?
[approaching footsteps]
My lord,
they have arrived.
Sure, I will grant your request.
I will let you take His Royal Highness.
[Mu-yeong] Your Royal Highness.
You cannot trust anyone.
We must leave this place.
Your Royal Highness.
[man] Crown Prince Lee Chang,
come out at once!
[door creaks]
You have come a long way.
It is time to return to Hanyang.
[approaching footsteps]
Are they not palace guards?
Thank you for guarding the criminal.
As per the King's command,
I shall escort him to prison.
Bind the traitor!
[servants] Yes, sir.
How dare you?
[Ahn Hyeon] Who?
Who is the traitor?
A palace guard,
who should serve the nation and the King,
gave into his personal greed
and became Cho Hak-ju's lapdog.
For oppressing the Crown Prince,
the heir to the throne,
and disrupting the core values
of this nation,
you deserve to be executed.
Execute him!
[swords rasping]
What do you think you are doing?
[grunting]
[yells, grunts]
Sangju is my hometown
and where I currently reside.
I urge you, Your Royal Highness,
to rest peacefully for tonight.
[sighs]
There is no time to rest.
You should rest
and let your body recover.
How else...
will you fight the chief palace guard?
What do you mean?
Yesterday,
a homing pigeon
delivered this secret letter
from the chief palace guard.
He said Your Royal Highness
was headed this way
and that I should lock you up
until he arrives.
The chief palace guard
could not have known
that I was headed here.
[sighs]
One of your companions...
is Cho Hak-ju's mole.
Thus,
you must not let anyone know
what we just discussed.
[groaning]
[grunting]
None of you shall survive.
Not a single one.
Not only you, but your families...
will be trapped in Gyeongsang,
catch the disease, and be decapitated.
[grunts]
[magistrate] What have you done?
How could you massacre palace guards
delivering the King's command?
Do you think Lord Cho Hak-ju
will let you get away with this?
He will accuse you of treason
and turn Sangju into a bloodbath!
Cho Hak-ju has already abandoned Sangju.
He has abandoned not only Sangju,
but also the east and west regions
of Gyeongsang and the people therein.
What do you mean?
Do you think all those soldiers
blocked off Mungyeong Saejae
just to stop me?
My lord, we have a big problem.
[crowd shouting]
Yangsan, Gyeongju, Daegu,
Hapcheon, Changnyeong...
They came from various parts
of the southern region
to escape the epidemic.
All of them were hit by the epidemic?
If Changnyeong was already hit,
the infected will get here in two days
or as soon as tonight.
[sighs] You must open the gate
and let them in.
If all parts of Gyeongsang were hit,
there will be more and more refugees.
How are we going to house
and feed them all?
Once we run out of food,
they will start looting.
There will be mayhem inside the fortress.
Then do you plan to sit back
and watch them die?
[crowd clamoring]
[crowd wailing]
If you do not open the gate now,
people of Sangju outside the fortress
will also be in danger.
Open the gate.
We cannot open the gate.
At least the people inside must survive.
I am sure Cho Hak-ju said the same thing
when he closed Mungyeong Saejae.
That at least they must survive.
This is a small sacrifice
for the greater good.
Who are you to decide whom to sacrifice?
If you lock the gate, those outside
will catch the disease and die.
The people inside will be trapped
and die of starvation.
I am the magistrate of Sangju!
No.
You are no longer qualified
to run this place.
- What?
- I cannot let everyone die
because of an incompetent official.
I will protect Sangju and the people
from now on.
By what right?
I am the Crown Prince.
I strip you of the title
from this moment forth!
It is the Crown Prince's command.
Escort the magistrate out.
Lord Ahn,
you cannot do this.
You will regret this.
Move aside!
What will you do?
Even if we open the gate,
the inside of the fortress is not spacious
enough to shelter the refugees
as well as the people outside.
You are correct.
It cannot house everyone.
If we are to save everyone,
we must protect the entirety of Sangju.
The infected will soon come charging in.
How can we protect all of Sangju?
The diseased are corpses during the day
and come alive only at night.
They also fear water and fire.
If we take advantage of that,
we can stop them.
The south of Sangju
is surrounded by water.
If we guard both Byeongseong Stream
and Unpo Wetland against them,
we all can...
survive.
[crowd clamoring]
[cheering]
[grunts]
[clears throat]
You cannot do this.
How could you tell noblemen to bear arms?
This is nonsense.
It is the Crown Prince's command.
[men grumbling]
[scoffs] We should be holding books,
not something like this.
[sighs]
[metal clanging]
[indistinct chatter]
[grunting]
Okay, a little more.
This is tiring.
Okay, you should go.
[servant] I will check the perimeter.
[horse neighs]
Giddyap.
[court lady] I think the baby will be born
by the end of today.
- Will it be a boy?
- We are not sure--
Report to me only when a baby boy is born.
Yes, Your Majesty.
[rain pattering]
[woman groans]
[groaning intensifies]
[woman screaming]
[grunts]
[screaming]
[screaming intensifies]
[crying] Mom!
[baby crying]
The baby is here!
Thank goodness. She has been
in so much pain since last night.
I know. It must have been so hard for her.
[baby stops crying]
It is cold outside. Return to your rooms.
The baby stopped crying.
Is something wrong?
Both the mother and the baby are safe.
She is nursing the baby now, so go back.
Is it a boy or a girl?
It is a girl.
- Gosh.
- Why does it have to be a girl?
Who cares if it is a girl?
It does not matter
as long as the baby is healthy.
[gasps] Darn it. Oh, no.
You are so...
[sighs]
Oh. Thank goodness.
It did not damage Her Majesty's robe.
Thank goodness.
If you had left a single stain on it,
it would have turned into a pile of ashes.
What do you mean?
One time,
I saw them burning
Her Majesty's precious silk robe.
Really?
Yes, for real.
The head court lady burned it herself.
It only had a tiny blood stain on it.
What a waste.
My gosh.
I could die a happy girl
if I could wear something like this once.
[sucks teeth] What could lowly girls
like us possibly expect?
[sighs] We shall go.
Okay.
[both gasp]
[both] Your Majesty.
If you are done cleaning, you may leave.
[both] Yes, my lady.
[water splashing]
My lady,
will I really serve Her Majesty?
Why someone lowly like me,
instead of a court lady?
Do not speak,
and focus on serving Her Majesty.
Why are you so slow?
My apologies, Your Majesty.
[maid gasps]
[court lady] How dare you?
[maid shudders]
What do you think?
My baby looks very healthy, does he not?
Please have mercy, Your Majesty!
Oh.
[panting]
- My lord, I shall carry that for you.
- There is no need to. Just go.
What do you think?
This is plenty, is it not?
[laughing]
[Beom-pal sighs]
[Seo-bi gasps]
You are incredible.
[laughing]
How did you pick nothing but weeds?
What?
What? Look closely.
I only picked what you told me to pick.
You must be tired. You should rest.
[stammers] But...
I will go and pick it myself.
But... what do you mean I should rest?
[Beom-pal groans]
How can a man rest
when everyone else is working?
Seo-bi!
[Beom-pal groans]
Is that not more than enough?
There are more medicinal herbs
that I must find.
What more are you looking for?
False lily of the valley.
His Royal Highness's wounds
have not healed yet.
I need that plant.
So, it is for the Crown Prince.
[Beom-pal grunts]
Seo-bi.
Seo-bi. [grunts]
I am hurt as well.
You got hurt while running away.
[Beom-pal sighs]
No... You...
You cannot go that way.
[pants] The magistrate's office
said that path is dangerous
and strictly forbids entering it.
[Seo-bi]
It is not like there are tigers there.
What is dangerous about it?
Who knows?
It is called Frozen Valley or something.
Maybe it is haunted or something.
We should go back.
What did you just say?
What? What do you mean?
Did you say, "Frozen Valley"?
Yes.
That valley up there is
called Frozen Valley.
[Beom-pal panting]
Wait. Wait.
Why is she so fearless?
Well,
that is her charm.
[pants] Seo-bi.
[Beom-pal grunts]
Wait, Seo-bi.
- [wind gusting]
- [leaves rustling]
[Beom-pal grunting]
[chimes ringing]
It is chilly.
It already feels like winter here.
[Beom-pal panting]
A place where it is foggy
all year round...
[chimes rattle]
Wait, Seo... Seo-bi.
Hold on.
Seo... Seo-bi!
Seo... Seo-bi.
[Beom-pal panting]
[groans]
[chimes rattle]
[Beom-pal whimpering]
It is too cold! It is so cold!
[panting]
The resurrection plant...
What? What did you say?
[Beom-pal groaning]
This is the plant.
This plant brought the dead back to life.
This is the plant
that brought the dead back to life!
What is that?
[chimes rattling]
- [thud]
- [both gasp]
[gunshot]
[amused gasp]
When aiming a gun,
you must keep the muzzle, the barrel,
and the arm in a straight line
as much as you can.
He is good with guns.
[Deok-seong]
He used to be a member of Chakho.
He's the one from Sumang Village
that I spoke of.
[Yeong-sin] Fire!
[gunshots]
Do you know him?
No.
I do not know him.
[Yeong-sin] Fire!
[gunshots]
Everyone, listen up!
The sun will set soon!
Check your surroundings one more time!
Do not leave your post for any reason!
- Do you understand?
- [men] Yes, sir!
[men grunting]
[officer] Cast off the boats!
Two! One! Two!
One!
Two!
[tense music playing]
[wind gusting]
The ones who went on the reconnaissance
have not yet returned.
[rumbling]
[guard] We have arrived, my lord.
[horse snorting]
THE FIRST GATE OF MUNGYEONG SAEJAE
Welcome, Chief State Councillor.
What is the status?
Sangju is still safe from the epidemic.
[thud]
- [thud]
- [horse neighs]
[horse whinnying]
[thudding continues]
[thudding intensifies]
Your Royal Highness.
The sun will rise soon, and we only need
to hang on a little longer.
[sighs]
Your Royal Highness.
[men gasp]
[horse neighs]
It's the horse of the servant
who was out to survey the area.
[officer] Let it through.
The blood has not dried yet.
They will be here soon.
[explosion]
The signal fire has been lit.
Sound the drums!
[drum thumping]
[tense music playing]
Please rise.
It is very cold outside.
You should get inside, my lord.
[birds squawking]
- It is the sun!
- The sun is up!
[sighs]
We must prepare for tonight,
so I will tell them to get some rest.
- Everyone, come in!
- [men cheering]
- We made it!
- Let us pull out for today!
[indistinct chatter]
[men] One, two. One, two.
Now that the sun has risen,
let us get some sleep.
Let us eat some delicious food!
Let us go.
Do you think it is over?
Pack up quickly,
and prepare for the evening!
[men] Yes, sir!
[birds squawking]
[distant growling]
[Beom-pal whimpers]
[Beom-pal]
How are they out during the day?
It was not the sun.
It was the temperature.
[rumbling]
[distant growling]
[growling]
[growling intensifies]
[theme music playing]
[music ends]